Taeko Harada

Software Developer

Calgary, AB. taecooo512@gmail.com | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/taeko-harada/ GitHub: https://github.com/TaekoHarada/ | Portfolio: https://portfolio2-ebon-pi.vercel.app/

SUMMARY

Software Developer | Al Enthusiast | Bilingual (Japanese & English)

Currently pursuing a Software Development diploma at SAIT in Calgary, Canada to restart my career.

Previously worked in Japan as a system administrator, web designer, Flash creator, and system architect.

Now focused on exploring ways to leverage Gen Al capabilities, while learning test automation (Selenium), mobile development (Kotlin), and web development (React, TypeScript).

I see great potential for improvement in Al's Japanese capabilities, as I encounter translation issues in my daily use while also noticing significant advancements in some Gen Al tools.

SKILLS

Languages: Kotlin • JavaScript • TypeScript • Python • Java • C# • HTML5 • CSS

Frameworks: Selenium • Jetpack compose • React • Next.js • Bootstrap • Tailwind

.NET MAUI

Libraries/Tools: OpenCV, MediaPipe

EXPERIENCE

Software Development Student | Southern Alberta Institute of Technology (SAIT)

Sep 2023 - Present (Expected graduation: Dec 2024)

- Developing strong foundation in software development principles and practices
- Capstone Project: Order Management System (Web system using Next.js and Firestore)
 - Designed system architecture and established development environment

- Created coding guidelines to ensure consistent and efficient development practices
- Collaborated with team members to deliver a high-quality, scalable solution

Information Technology System Administrator (Japan)

Feb 2009 - Feb 2011

System administrator at the Information Technology Department of Kawasaki Heavy Industries, Ltd.

- <u>Troubleshooting and Collaboration</u>: Facilitated communication between users and developers to solve critical system issues and enhance software performance.
- <u>Improving and developing the systems</u>: Collaborated with users, developers, and the IT strategy department, ensuring alignment with organizational goals.
- <u>Process Improvement</u>: Developed and implemented an efficient file-deleting script, reducing processing time by 10x.
- <u>Database Management</u>: Expanded Oracle database table spaces, ensuring scalability for increasing data volumes.

Flash Creator (Japan)

Oct 2007 - Jan 2009

Creating Flash contents by using ActionScript for mobile phones.

Web Designer (Japan)

Apr 2007 - Sep 2007

Designing and coding websites with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and PHP.

Student Tutor (Japan)

Apr 2011 - Dec 2011

Teaching Mathematics for junior high school students.

EDUCATION

Software Development, Diploma

Southern Alberta Institute of Technology (SAIT)

Sep 2023 – Present (Expected graduation: Dec 2024)

Applied Mathematics, Bachelor of Science

Osaka Women's University

Web Design

Digital Hollywood University

LANGUAGES

Japanese (Native), English (B2)

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Cloud Practitioner (2024)